nationalcity.com 2004-12-15

# Privacy Notice - About National City - National City Corporation

|  |   
---  
|   
---  
|  |   
---  
 Careers  
|  |   
---  
 News  
|  |   
---  
 Investor relations  
|  |   
---  
 Community relations  
|  |   
---  
 Diversity  
|  |   
---  
 Community reinvestment  
|  |  |   
---  
|   
---|---  
|   
  
---  
---  
|   
---  
|  |  |  | Privacy notice  
---  
|  |  |  |   
---  
The basis of each customer relationship at National City is built on trust. You have chosen to do business with National City, and we guard that relationship with great care, beginning with the information you have chosen to share with us.   
   
Jump to ...  
Overview  
Information we collect  
Security procedures  
Information we disclose  
Fair Credit Reporting Act Disclosure   
|  | National City's Pledge  
Effective date and changes  
National City companies  
Frequently asked questions  
|  |   
---|---  
|   
|  |  | Terms & conditions |  |   
|  |  | Review the terms and conditions of NationalCity.com. |   
|  |  |  |   
|   
|   
---|---  
|   
|  |  | Email fraud: Phishing scams |  |   
|  |  | Learn how to avoid becoming a victim of bogus emails. |   
|  |  | Learn more  |   
|  |  |  |   
|   
|  |  |  |   
---|---  
|   
|  |  OPT-OUT: We will not share your nonpublic personal information with others as defined below. National City, on your behalf, has exercised your right to opt-out under 12 CFR Part 40, Privacy of Consumer Financial Information.   
---  
   
Overview  
  
National City does not share information about you outside of our National City companies unless permitted by Title V of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act of 1999 and other applicable laws and regulations.

National City Corporation, its family of financial services companies (“affiliates”) and employees, are dedicated to protecting the privacy of your nonpublic personal information. We maintain information about you in order to provide you with the most effective and convenient access to our broad range of financial products and services. We want you to understand what information we collect, and how we use and protect it. This notice serves as a standard for all National City employees for collection, use, retention and security of nonpublic personal consumer information.   
  
Information we collect  
  
“Nonpublic personal information” is information about you that we obtain in connection with providing a financial product or service. Such information includes for example, account balance, income, assets, insurance premiums, payment history and overdraft history. 

We may collect nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources: 

  * Information that you provide to us, such as on applications or other forms 
  * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates or others, or 
  * Information from others, such as credit bureaus, real estate appraisers, and employers

Our security procedures  
To maintain security of customer information, we restrict access to your personal and account information to persons who need to know that information to provide you products or services. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to guard information.   
Back to top  
   
Information we disclose  
National City does not disclose nonpublic personal information about you to any companies that are not members of our corporate family (“third parties”), except as permitted by federal law, specifically Title V of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act of 1999. The confidentiality of your nonpublic personal information will continue to be maintained consistent with this privacy notice even if you decide to close your account(s), your account becomes inactive, or when you otherwise cease to do business with us. 

National City works with a variety of third parties to bring you financial services. We disclose information about you as necessary to fulfill these third party service agreements. For example, we may disclose information about you to third parties that assist us in servicing or maintaining your loan or deposit account, or other business relationship, such as printing checks or billing you for loan payments. We may also disclose information about you to governmental entities, such as sending annual income statements to the IRS, and to other third parties such as credit bureaus, or in response to subpoenas. 

We may disclose all of the information we collect, as described above, to third parties that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions, such as insurance providers, with whom we have joint marketing agreements in order to make a variety of financial services available to you*. These third parties must agree to strict confidentiality provisions to assure the protection of your information. Because we already limit the sharing of your nonpublic personal information as outlined above, no action is necessary on your part to limit such sharing.   
Back to top  

Fair Credit Reporting Act Disclosure*  
We share information about you with our affiliates. Under the Fair Credit Reporting Act you may direct us not to share certain credit information with our affiliates. Examples of the kind of credit information that you may direct us not to share include the nonpublic personal information you provide in your application or that we obtain about you from nonaffiliated third parties such as credit bureaus. If you don’t want such information shared you may write to us at National City Corporation, Attention: Office of Consumer Privacy, P.O. Box 4068, Kalamazoo, MI 49009. Please provide your name, address, social security number and account number(s). 

(NOTE: If you have previously requested that we restrict such sharing you do not need to make another request.)

Your request not to share credit information does not include information we are permitted to share by law, such as information related solely to our experiences or transactions with you. Your account balance and payment history are examples of transaction and experience information that we are always permitted to share with our affiliates.   
Back to top  

National City’s Pledge to You   
We believe that your privacy should never be compromised. At the same time, we want to offer you the array of financial products and services you need to accomplish your financial goals. We believe we can do both by adhering to the provisions of this privacy notice.   
Back to top  
   
Effective date and changes  
The effective date of this Privacy Notice is provided below. Any updates or changes to the Notice will be posted on this web site. Consumers who are National City customers will be notified of updates and changes in accordance with federal law.  
Back to top  
   
National City companies  
  
National City Bank, National City Bank of Kentucky, Inc., National City Insurance Agency of Kentucky, Inc., NatCity Investments, Inc., National City Bank of Pennsylvania, National City Insurance Agency of Pennsylvania, Inc., National City Bank of Southern Indiana, Sterling Private Investments, Inc., National City Bank of Indiana, National City Mortgage Co., National City Home Loan Services, Inc., First Franklin Financial Corporation, The Madison Bank & Trust Company, National City Bank of the Midwest, Allegiant Insurance Services, Allegiant Investment Counselors, Inc., Allegiant Investment Company, NatCity Insurance Services, Inc., National City Insurance Group, Inc., National City Investment Management Company®, National City Mortgage Services Co., Alliance Title Agency, LLC, New England Trust Company, N.A., National City Abstract, LLC, Access Financial Corp., Red Capital Markets, Inc., Capstone Realty Advisers, LLC, Provident Auto Leasing Company, Provident Auto Rental Company, LLC, NatCity Trust Company of Delaware   

*Vermont Residents Only: In Vermont the information we disclose under joint marketing agreements must be limited to your name, contact information, and information about our own transactions and experiences with you. Your consent is required before we can share certain credit information about you with our affiliates. We are permitted to share information which is not a credit report under Vermont law without your consent, such as information related solely to our transactions and experiences with you. 

**California Residents:** We will not disclose or share information about California residents without first providing you with a California Privacy Notice and honoring your choice unless such sharing or disclosure is permitted by applicable law.  
Back to top  
  
(rev 12/2004)  
   
**Frequently Asked Questions**  
  
National City is dedicated to protecting the privacy of your nonpublic personal information. Federal law establishes rules for sharing customer information. It requires financial institutions to deliver a privacy notice explaining the institutions privacy policy and practices to new customers and annually thereafter. We believe that your privacy should never be compromised. National City’s privacy notice describes how we collect and use your nonpublic personal information. It will help you understand the careful attention we devote to handling and protecting your nonpublic personal information. 

Here are answers to some frequently asked questions about privacy to help you understand National City’s position on this important issue. 

1\. **Does the National City Privacy Notice cover all my National City accounts?**

Yes, however, you may receive more than one copy of the notice from National City if you have several accounts or do business with more than one National City company. This helps us to ensure that all customers receive it.  
Back to top

2\. **Does National City’s Privacy Notice apply to businesses?**

No. The privacy notice applies to individual customers who obtain products and services for personal, family or household purposes. It does not apply to business customers, including Sole Proprietors when the purpose is business related.   
Back to top

3\. **What is “n _onpublic personal information_ ”? **

_“Nonpublic personal information”_ is information about you that we obtain in connection with providing a financial product or service. For example, this might include information such as account balances, income, assets, and insurance premiums. Generally speaking, nonpublic personal information is information that is not available in public records.   
Back to top

4\. **Do you sell information about me to other companies?**

No. We will not sell information about you. We honor the trust that you have placed in National City to keep information about you confidential.   
Back to top

5\. **When does National City share nonpublic information about me with third parties?**

We limit the ways that we share information to the purposes permitted by law. These permissible information sharing exceptions fall into three categories: 

  * **Servicing and Joint Marketing:** **** We share information with companies that perform services on our behalf, like check printers. We also share information with companies that we hire to help us market our National City products and services. National City is able to offer you a broader selection of product and service options to help you achieve your financial goals when we contract with select financial institutions that offer financial services. Any information shared for servicing or joint marketing is pursuant to an agreement with the third party that requires them to adhere to strict confidentiality terms. They are not permitted to use information provided to them for any purpose whatsoever other than for the specific reason it was provided to them by National City.

  * **Processing and Servicing Transactions:** Information is shared, as necessary, to service and process financial products and services that are requested by you, such as wire transfers or loan applications. Information is also shared in connection with maintaining and servicing your accounts, such as statement preparation, complaint resolution, or debt collection.

  * **Other Lawful or Required Purposes:** This category includes a variety of permissible sharing situations, such as when you request or consent to have information shared, or when we share information with our auditors, attorneys or accountants, government regulators, in response to subpoenas, and other circumstances where sharing information is permitted or required by law.  
Back to top

6\. **What is third party opt-out and why do some financial institutions offer this opt-out to their customers when National City does not offer it?**

Did you notice the box checked at the top of our privacy notice? National City believes your privacy is so important that we have effectively opted out for you. You may receive notices from other financial institutions with whom you do business that include a third party information sharing opt-out provision. National City is not required to provide you with a third party information sharing opt-out choice because we already restrict our information sharing practices to those allowed by law and discussed above in question five. In other words, our sharing practices are more conservative than those of institutions that must provide their customers with third party opt-out.   
Back to top

7\. **Why does National City share information about me with other National City companies**? 

There are many benefits to sharing information within our National City family of companies. These are just a few: 

  * **Fraud Prevention:** Sharing information amongst National City companies helps us to prevent fraud. Your accounts and your personal identity are better protected from thieves and imposters, and National City is less vulnerable to losses from fraud. Consumer fraud is costly. Controlling it keeps your costs down. 
  * **Enhanced Service:** _ ****_ Sharing information enables us to provide you with superior service. For example, our retail bank Call Centers are able to serve you faster and more efficiently when they have access to all of your bank relationships and account information. You have the convenience of calling just one number to have most of your banking questions answered. 
  * **Tailored Products and Services:** Knowledge of your account relationships, balances and transaction behavior helps us to identify what products and services may be most interesting to you. We use this information to keep you informed about those suited to you. It also helps us to identify and notify you when market conditions are favorable to you. For example, we can analyze the impact of lower interest rates on your mortgage and notify you when conditions are right for you to benefit financially from refinancing your home.   
Back to top

8\. **Which National City companies share information with each other?**

There is a list of National City companies at the end of our Privacy Notice (above). They are companies that provide various financial services, such as investments, mortgages, bank accounts, credit cards, securities brokerage services, trusts, insurance, student loans and more. Our Privacy Notice applies to individuals who have accounts with these companies. These are the National City companies that share information with each other.   
Back to top

9\. **How can I prevent information about me from being shared with other National City companies?**

This is discussed in the Fair Credit Reporting Act Disclosure included in our Privacy Notice. You can limit some information shared with other National City companies. You can direct us not to share information about you that we obtained from your credit application or third party sources, such as information provided by credit bureaus. Refer to our Privacy Notice for instructions about how to contact us to restrict information sharing with other National City companies. We respect and will honor your preference. When you direct us not to share this type of information, we are still permitted to share information based on our transactions and experiences with you. This is important for the reasons discussed above in question 7. Note: If you have previously requested that we restrict such sharing, you do not need to make another request.   
Back to top

10\. **Does the Privacy Notice apply to internet usage also?**

Yes. National City’s Privacy Notice applies in its entirety to Internet and PC transactions.  
Back to top

11\. **What if I believe that the personal or financial information that National City keeps on me is incorrect?**

Please contact your National City representative, branch, office or call center if any of your information is incorrect or if any information changes, such as your name or address. National City will research your concern and make any necessary corrections.   
Back to top  
|  |  |   
---|---  
| Identity theft information   
|   
|   
| 

Identity theft 101    
Learn how to guard against this damaging crime.

Keeping your information safe 

Minimize your risk of identity theft  
  
Federal Trade Commission [](http://www.sec.gov/rules/final/34-42974.htm)  
The national resource for identity theft

Other identity theft resources American Bankers Association Consumer Connection [](http://www.sec.gov/rules/final/34-42974.htm)

AARP [](http://www.sec.gov/rules/final/34-42974.htm)

U.S. Department of Education [](http://www.sec.gov/rules/final/34-42974.htm)  
  
|   
---|---  
|  Frequently asked questions  
|   
|  **Does the National City Privacy Notice cover all my National City accounts? **

**Does National City’s Privacy Notice apply to businesses?**

**What is “ _non_ _public personal information_ ”? **

Do you sell information about me to other companies? ****

**When does National City share nonpublic information about me with third parties? **

**What is third party opt-out and why do some financial institutions offer this opt-out to their customers when National City does not offer it? **

Why does National City share information about me with other National City companies?

**Which National City companies share information with each other? **

How can I prevent information about me from being shared with other National City companies?

**Does the Privacy Notice apply to internet usage also? **

**What if I believe that the personal or financial information that National City keeps on me is incorrect? **
